<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Pavan Chennagiri</title>
    <link>https://pavancm.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Pavan Chennagiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Pavan Chennagiri</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pavancm.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization with Optimistic Descent Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://pavancm.github.io/project/omd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavancm.github.io/project/omd/</guid>
      <description>This work focuses on the review and applications of extra gradient methods popularly referred to as optimistic descent algorithms. First we introduce the concept optimistic mirror descent (OMD) and provide intuition as well as motivation behind this concept. Second we evaluate the performance of optimistic methods across a host of applications. In particular we compare the performance of OMD in convex, non-convex and saddle point problem settings. Lastly we observe that OMD has certain fundamental limitations and only outperforms the existing methods under certain specific considerations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Scene Statistics in Adversarial Learning</title>
      <link>https://pavancm.github.io/project/nss_gan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavancm.github.io/project/nss_gan/</guid>
      <description>Synthesizing natural images using generative models such as Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) has received significant attention in the recent days due to advancements in deep learning. The existing generative models employ relatively simple loss functions derived from L1 /L2 norms during training due to it’s simplistic nature as well very desirable properties in statistics and estimation. However from the perceptual viewpoint mean squared error (L2 norm) has a very weak correlation with image quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA Sequencing using deep Recurrent Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://pavancm.github.io/project/dna_rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavancm.github.io/project/dna_rnn/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing by DNA translocation is an emerging technology which offers cheaper and faster devices for DNA sequencing. However, precisely determining the bases present in the sequence from noisy and lengthy electric signals is particu larly challenging and offers an interesting research problem. In this project two basecalling methods DeepNano and Chiron are evaluated and the fundamental advantages and drawbacks associated with them are analyzed. Chiron uses a combination of CNN-RNN model as opposed to RNN in case of Deepnano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics of Optical Flow</title>
      <link>https://pavancm.github.io/project/optical-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavancm.github.io/project/optical-flow/</guid>
      <description>Video Quality Assessment (VQA) is an emerging area of research which aims at establishing objective quality evaluation methodologies for predicting video quality. Objective quality assessment algorithms have several applications like real-time monitoring of quality in networks, improve quality of experience (QoE) for users, evaluating compression algorithms etc. In this project only No Reference approach was considered where reference video or pristine video is not available during evaluation phase. Employing statistics of optical flow estimates to predict video quality was analyzed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Image Colorization</title>
      <link>https://pavancm.github.io/project/colorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pavancm.github.io/project/colorization/</guid>
      <description>This project was an implementation of a deep colorization model using multi-layered perceptron model. Model was trained by extracting three types of features extracted from patches. Low level features were representative of low textured regions, mid level features for textured parts and high level features conveyed semantic information. The model was trained on images obtained from SUN database.
This project was undertaken as part of Machine Learning for Signal Processing (E9 205) course during Aug-Dec 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>